Tyler T. Mullen

Email: Tmullen493@gmail.com | Phone: 612-644-7902 |

Location: New Hope, MN 55427

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-mullen-94905553/| GitHub: https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen| Website: https://Tyler-

Mullen.github.io/singlePagePortfolio/

SUMMARY

Web developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science and experience coding sorting algorithms and a compiler for mini-pascal using Java. Excels at teaching end-users how to use technologies and working in fast-paced environments with demanding deadlines that require communication with co-workers and clients. Leverages coding and troubleshooting skills to create web pages, applications and software.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient with Java, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Firebase, phpMyAdmin, API's, Git, Git Bash, SQL, React.js, Express.js and MySQLWorkBench, Moment.js, Axios.js, Sorting Algorithms, MERN, User Training and Full Stack Development

PROJECTS

Friend Finder | https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/friendFinder https://vast-garden-65226.herokuapp.com/

- A ten-question quiz that matches the user to a set of friends that is saved in a JSON file and saves the user's scores for later.
- Uses Express.js to route the results to the JSON file and JSON to store objects form the API.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JSON, Express.js.

LIRI Search Bot | https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/liri-node-app

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1l0zRhITL4Mlh4nKGg8R3EvpmeqNOs8QZ/view

- Allows the user to run searches for concert dates, movie information, and song information.
- Uses Spotify's API to search Spotify's database and Axios to search Bands-in-town and OMDB's database.
- Node.js, Moment, Spotify API, Axios, JavaScript.

Train Scheduler https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/Train-Scheduler https://Tyler-Mullen.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

- Adds trains to a schedule, displaying name, destination, and next arrival.
- Sends data to, and pull data from, firebase to display all scheduled trains.
- Firebase, Moment, JavaScript, CSS, HTML.

EXPERIENCE

Back of House Team Member-Chick-Fil-A - Bloomington, MN

2017 - 2019

- Cultivating strong relationships with co-workers and demonstrating a calm composure during busy and stressful periods.
- First team member (out of 35) to complete a rigorous online training program set up by franchise operator.

<u>Technical Consultant</u> – Allina Health – Minneapolis, MN

2016 - 2017

- Assisted approximately fifty Allina Health patients per day by recovering login information, resetting passwords, and changing account information.
- Knowledgeable in Allina Health's Patient Portal and MyChart, and explained features and benefits to patients.
- Created and processed MyChart user login for new patients.

Intern - Lifeworks - Eagan, MN

2016 - 2016

- Relocated and rewired approximately twenty computers during the facility's reorganization.
- Installed Windows 8 updates onto all computers.
- Managed the personal login updates for all 150+ staff members across six offices to ensure they would not be affected by a recent security breach.
- Effectively communicated with staff and executed the setup of IT equipment.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, St. Paul, MN - Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, currently enrolled.

Augsburg College, Minneapolis, MN – Bachelors of Arts In Computer Science, graduated 2016.